# Shruti Kamalam Ramamoorthy

# Corporate Lawyer

Corporate Lawyer with 6.3 years of experience in the financial services industry. Drafted, Vetted and Negotiated all forms of agreements & contracts related to Debt financing and Collateral for Debentures, Short -Term and Long -Term Loans. Currently form a part of the legal team of investment banking division at Deustche India Pvt Limited which involves legal documentation for Derivatives transactions. Skilled in managing legal affairs including due diligence, contract documentation, liaison, dynamics of SEBI regulations & other statutory obligations. Willingness to take on added responsibilities to meet team goals and adaptive to new situations and challenges to best enhance organizational brand.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

#### Jan 2022 - Current

#### **Associate**

#### Deutsche India Private Limited, Mumbai (Deutsche Bank Group)

- Reviewing, drafting, vetting, and negotiating client facing Non-Disclosure Agreements (NDAs) including Master NDAs, back-to-back NDAs/joinders, and non-reliance Letters.
- Reviewing, drafting, vetting, and negotiating ISDA Master Agreements and related Amendments, Cleared Derivatives Execution Agreement, Credit Support Annex, Foreign Exchange Prime Brokerage Agreements and related documentation including Double Give Up agreements for clients in the EMEA region.
- Reviewing the work of two junior team colleagues by providing feedback and comments on the drafting of Foreign Exchange Prime Brokerage related Agreements.
- Reviewing Constitutional Documents and ensuring that all requisite corporate consents and approvals are in place prior to finalization of agreements and subsequent trading
- Liaising and Coordinating with Risk Division of Bank and other internal departments/stakeholders as necessary.
- Building relationships with the client by understanding their needs and working closely with clients to improve their satisfaction
- Understanding business and regulatory requirements by ensuring that legal documentation functions are performed in line with those requirements.

# Nov 2018 – Jan 2022

# Assistant Manager

# Vistra ITCL (India) Limited, Mumbai

- Dealt with various banks/NBFCs/FIs in shaping various structured and project financing deals in relation to Debentures, Consortium Lending, Short-Term Loans and Long-Term Loans.
- Drafted, Vetted and Negotiated security documents including Security
  Trustee Agreement, Mortgage Deed, Share Pledge Agreement,
  Declaration cum undertaking, Memorandum of Entry by deposit of Title
  deeds, Deed of Hypothecation, Power of Attorney, Deed of Guarantee
  and subsequent amendments.
- Drafted, Vetted and Negotiated debenture related documents including Debenture Trustee Agreement and Debenture Trust Deed.
- Vetted all forms of legal documentation, letters, CHG forms, Title Search Report, Valuation Report, ROC Search report, Board resolutions in relation to Long-Term and Short-Term borrowings by companies & issuance of debentures.
- Conducted due diligence and assisted clients in the listing of debt securities on Stock Exchange portals.
- Coordinated with Lender and Legal Counsel for closure of documentation and ensured that legal documents are executed in compliance with rules and regulations.



#### Contact

#### **Address**

Akruti Orchid Park, Sakinaka, Mumbai, India 400072

#### Phone

+919099060131

#### E-mail

shrutikr1965@gmail.com

#### Skills

- Drafting & Negotiation skills and eye for detail
- Communication skills both Oral and Written
- Problem Solving
- Interpersonal skills and team player

# Personal details

#### Date of Birth

1<sup>st</sup> May 1992

# **Marital Status**

Married

# Languages

English, Hindi, Tamil, Malayalam & Gujarati

# July 2017-Nov 2018

# **Assistant Manager**

# Axis Trustee Services Limited, Mumbai (Axis Bank Subsidiary)

- Drafted and Vetted all Security, Loan and Debenture documents in relation to short term and loan term borrowings by Corporates.
- Drafted NOCs, Lending Confirmation Notices, Credit Rating Revision Letters, Conditions Precedent Compliance Letters, Security confirmation letters and managed all professional correspondence with clients on a regular basis catering to their requirements.
- Coordinated with lenders, legal counsels, and the borrower to ensure smooth execution of documentation
- Ensured compliance of conditions precedent to issuance of debentures and checked pre disbursement checklists and contents such as board resolutions, various compliance certificates etc.
- Ensured creation of appropriate charges on the assets of the Borrower including Mortgage, Hypothecation, Pledge and Guarantee.
- Monitored security/security cover and financial covenants including seeking periodic information from companies and ensured compliance with SEBI regulations in case of listed debentures.

#### **INTERNSHIPS**

- AZB & Partners, Mumbai (Oct 2015)
- Nanavati & Nanavati Associates, Ahmedabad (Jan 2014)
- Frontline Corporation Limited (Dec 2014)
- Practicing Lawyer Mr. Sharvil Girish Pathak, Ahmedabad District Court (Jan 2013)
- Yuva Unstoppable, NGO, Ahmedabad (Dec 2012)

#### **EDUCATION**

## Aug 2016-May 2017

## L.L.M: Corporate Law

Narsee Monjee Institute of Management Studies - Mumbai

June 2011-

B.A.L.L.B (Hons.): Law

May 2016

Maharaja Sayajirao University of Baroda - Vadodara

Dec 2012 -

**CS Inter: Company Secretary** 

June 2016

Institute of Company Secretaries of India - Ahmedabad

June 2009-

Class 12: High School

May 2010

Maharaja Agrasen Vidyalaya - Ahmedabad

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

Mar 2017	Certificate course on Contract Law
June 2014	Certificate course on Legal Drafting
June 2014	Certificate course on Competition Law
July 2014	Certificate Course on International Environmental Law

Sep 2013 Diploma in Cyber Law.

### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Earned Recognition Award in the legal team for the year 2022 at Deutsche India Pvt Limited.
- Awarded the "Budding Talent Award" in the legal team within my very first year at Vistra ITCL India Limited in 2019
- Secured 1st rank during my L.L.M (Corporate Law) at the NMIMS Institute of Management Studies- School of Law
- Secured 4th rank during my B.A.L.L.B (hons.) at Maharaja Sayajirao University of Baroda.

# **EXTRACURRICULARS**

- Participated in many marathons, including India's biggest "Standard Chartered Mumbai Marathon".
- Participated in 2 days Mediation Workshop held at College level.
- Participated in Lei Ipsum- Legal Insight, Business Instinct held at NMIMS, School of Business Management, Mumbai
- Participated in 'National Moot Court Competition' held at Nirma University, as the Mooter at Ahmedabad, Gujarat.